Gaung Jagad

gaung.jgd@gmail.com | (+62)87880930709 | linkedin.com/in/gaungi

OBJECTIVE

Software engineer with more than 3 years of work experience specializing in automation testing with a background in ERP and e-commerce industry. Proficient in full-stack web development, performance testing, and automation CI/CD with familiarity in Java, Python, and JavaScript. I am seeking to join a company where I can make meaningful contributions to its development while continuing to enhance my professional skills and knowledge.

EXPERIENCES

Software Development Engineer in Test | Blibli

Nov 2022 - Present

- Contribute to the improvement of automation framework in QA Research and Development
- Build internal tools focusing on engineering productivity
- Deliver training and support for QA squads on building test automation
- Identify root causes of automation issues and provide solutions
- Maintain thousands of automated jobs using Jenkins
- Develop frontend and backend services for internal applications
- Script performance and concurrency test using Jmeter
- Utilize manual testing to identify issues before deployment
- Placed 2nd in internal hackathon building automation to detect content issues, replacing manual bug bashes and saving over 200 QA engineers' time.

Business Analyst | Arkana

Jan 2022 - Oct 2022

- Identify business requirements and provide solutions
- Develop requirement documentation ensuring products meet customer expectations
- Manage user acceptance testing to deliver highly functional products
- Provide functional and technical training for users and new employees

Software Engineer | Arkana

Apr 2021 - Dec 2021

- Build custom Odoo ERP modules focused on healthcare industry
- Develop backend and frontend web development
- Implement API integration with banking, WhatsApp, and payment gateway
- Provide functional support for default Odoo ERP modules

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming languages: Python, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript
- Frameworks: Spring, Next.js, React, Flask, Odoo, Tailwind CSS
- Database management: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- CI/CD: Bitbucket, Jenkins, Docker
- Project management: JIRA, Confluence, Trello
- Automation tools: Selenium, Playwright, Cucumber, Jmeter
- Others: Linux, Git, Grafana, Kibana, New Relic, Charles, VS Code, Node.js

EDUCATION

Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember

2016 - 2020

Bachelor's degree in Electrical Engineering